we need to use a
while loop to print hello twice
and we've been given a little bit of
code on lines one through three
we have a method greeting defined and it
appears that
this greeting method outputs the string
hello
on line 5 we also have a local variable
number of greetings and it's been
initialized to reference to integer 2.
let's just start by calling our greeting
method
and running our code
[Music]
so as you can see the greeting method
outputs hello
[Music]
now the greeting method outputs hello
just one time
and the problem requires us to print it
twice
and also use a while loop
so we can place our invocation of the
greeting method within a while loop
[Music]
now we want this while loop to iterate
two times
and we need to provide some type of
condition on line
seven to tell the while loop when to
stop
iterating
and while the condition that we provide
it is true
the loop will continue when the
condition returns false
then the while loop will stop iterating
so we can use the local variable that
was given to us
number of greetings to make sure we're
invoking the greeting method the
appropriate number of times
instead of initializing number of
greetings to zero
and incrementing as we iterate through
the loop
number of greetings has been initialized
to two
so instead we're going to want to
decrement the value of this variable
as we loop through
[Music]
and the syntax for that is
similar to incrementing
except we are using subtraction now on
line nine we are decrementing the value
of number of greetings by one each time
we iterate through this loop
and we know that we want two iterations
here because we want to invoke our
greeting method
twice so it makes sense for our
condition to be
while number of greetings
is greater than zero let's run the code
[Music]
and we've satisfied the problem
requirements by printing hello twice
it's important in cases like this to pay
attention to whether or not you're using
the proper comparison
for example if i had set my condition
to while number of greetings is greater
than or equal to zero
hello would have printed three times
[Music]
so take care to be precise when deciding
exactly what conditions and comparisons
to use for your loops